Contact



Bangalore, KA, 560100



+91-974-285-7340



jairc1796@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ jai-prakash-54a71261/

Skills

Java

Spring Boot

SQL

Data Structures

Rest API

Hibernate

Languages

English

Hindi

Tamil

JAI PRAKASH

A highly analytical individual with a strong apt for learning and collaborative skills, who wants to contribute to the company and also intends to improve and refine his skills while working with brilliant minds.

Bringing 3 years of FinTech work experience and strong programming skills.



WORK EXPERIENCE

July 2018 – July 2021 Senior Software Engineer, Infosys Bangalore

Client: Cisco, **Project Name**: PEP (Partner Engagement), **Location**: Bangalore. The website was about the engagement of the partners and partner managers and it and included functionalities like adding partners, managing bidding among various vendors.

- Worked as a Java Developer in Infosys for 3 yrs. Experience in Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate. Key role was developing the backend of client website (Cisco)
- Engaged in developing the user stories after discussing with the team lead on creating the sprints for development, testing, and deploying using the Agile methodology.
- Activities include Analysis, Designing, Coding and Unit Testing for all Enhancement related activities.
- Involved in Bug fixing and enhancements for the deployed code and extended support for maintenance of the application.
- Responsible for working with testing team for finding bugs and providing fixes.
 Involved in self learning towards included designing and developing a full-fledged Flight Booking application using Microservice Architecture which included functionalities of admin and user.
 - Front end using Angular framework and backend using Spring Boot framework, used MySQL database and deployed on AWS.
 - Users were able to book, update, cancel and download the tickets and also see the reports of all the user bookings.
 - Admin was able to login, manage Airlines, manage discounts, see reports of all the airlines.
 - Implemented Microservice Architecture, Swagger, Eureka and JWT for authentication and Zuul API gateway for routing.

July 2021-Present Software Engineer, Cognizant Bangalore

Working as a Full stack Developer in Cognizant for 6 months. Worked on enhancing an insurance company website with agile methodology. The Project is based on spring boot and Angular and is deployed on Cloud Forge and AWS platforms, using Bamboo for deployments.



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION

August 2014 – August 2018 Bachelor of Engineering

Dayananda Sagar Academy of Technology And

Management(DSATM) Bangalore

Specialization -: Computer Science and Engineering

Graduated with FIRST CLASS WITH DISTINCTION(74%)

March 2013- March 2014 Higher Secondary School

Kendriya Vidyalaya No.2 Surat

Specialization:-PCMC(Physic, Chemistry, Maths and

Computer Science)

Secured:- 76.8%

March 2011- March 2012 Secondary School

Kendriya Vidyalaya No.2 Surat

Secured: - 9.2 CGPA